<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Play School]]></title>
  <link href="http://chocks.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chocks.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-01T18:21:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://chocks.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chockalingam Eswaramurthy (Chocks)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/steve-jobs/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T22:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chocks.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/steve-jobs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Many years from now, history books will speak about a person who made a profound impact on the landscape of personal computing. This man changed the way humans perceive computing devices and digital content. At the time when I write this post there&#8217;s already a gazillion posts out there that sing the greatness of Steven Paul Jobs. So, leaving out the details, I am going to write about my take away from Steve Job&#8217;s life and career. One of the first things that struck me when I came across his videos was that he was an insanely optimistic person. In this video below, Jobs returns to work at Apple, Inc after a decade in 1997 and at this time Apple is doing really really bad.</p>

<iframe width="440" height="320" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/sPE3bJEuhSE " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<!-- more -->


<p>Their revenue is declining at an alarming rate of 2 billion per year (This was when Apple was making 12 billion per year, today Apple is making close to 400 billion!). He first lists all the negative things that people say about the company and its products, he then goes about explaining the same stuff in positive terms!! One year down the time at the 1998 Macworld keynote he explains how they went about reviving Apple by making reference to Maslow&#8217;s hierarchy of needs. He then shows off to the world what has been achieved - &#8220;Apple&#8217;s third consecutive profitable quarter&#8221;.
 <iframe width="440" height="320" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/gdYiqVzPjAc " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe> This is what I call as being &#8220;Insanely Optimistic&#8221;. If you had read the Steve Jobs biography by Walter Isaacson, he refers to this as &#8220;Reality distortion field&#8221; that was coined by former Apple employees.
Jobs was instrumental in conceiving the philosophy that &#8220;To change the world, you have to first believe that you can and the rest will follow&#8221;. As a programmer, I used to think of &#8220;design&#8221; in terms of structure and efficiency of algorithms and data structures. It never dawned upon me that user experience is the vital part of any device and the rest comes later. Almost every other company was under this assumption (some are still!) until Jobs made a shift in how things are thought. For a company like Apple and a leader like Jobs, customer experience comes first, he believed that most people never knew what they want until you show it to them. Then, he went about eliminating all the redundant features that would scare the hell out of a 60 year old grandma or a 3 year old kid. In doing so he created the &#8220;i&#8221; series of devices that propelled Apple to become the worlds most valuable company and set the bar for personal computing devices. I had personally never used a Apple device until I set foot in the US. And once I got them, there was no way I was getting a product of another company unless they had a superior user experience. For many, Steve Jobs is a Genius, a person who changed the world, but to me he is truly a Legend who was insanely optimistic. He may not have changed the world, but he did create iPhones and iPads, he may not have made them himself, instead he created an ecosystem where insanely great people can coexist to create amazing products.</p>

<p>One last Jobs video before I call it a post!</p>

<iframe width="440" height="320" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kYfNvmF0Bqw " frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My grandfather – A grandson’s eulogy]]></title>
    <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/2012/01/11/my-grandfather-a-grandsons-eulogy/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-11T19:52:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://chocks.github.com/blog/2012/01/11/my-grandfather-a-grandsons-eulogy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Life can always be seen through a pair of “positive lens” or with a pair of “negative lens”, make sure you always pick the positive pair and see shortcomings as opportunities”. This is the mantra that forms the foundation of my value system. I have heard this quote in one form or other in many motivational speeches, but the person who instilled this mantra in me right from my very young age was my grandfather.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
A self made, self-taught man with formal education of just 8th grade went on become a successful businessman and traveled across 60 countries in his career.
As my cousin once said, my grandfather’s life was a perfect story of rags-to-riches. Even after being immensely successful in life, he led a very simple life. His philosophy of success was a great family. His teachings in life were simple, just like Robin Sharma advises, my grandfather used to keep a routine of his mind and body. He was a going-to-bed-early-wake-up-early person. He was also a strict vegetarian; he once told me that he lived on raw spinach when he travelled abroad in 70’s.</p>

<p>My grandfather liked to challenge the obvious, because he believed and now I have to come to believe that great ideas are born by challenging the obvious and that will enable us to make an impact in the world.</p>

<p>I have probably learnt more from my grandfather than from my formal education.</p>

<p>Subroto Bagchi once wrote, “When great people move on, you don’t feel sad instead you feel a sense of vacuum”. This reflects my thoughts and loss accurately.</p>

<p>Though he’s not with us anymore, his teachings and values are etched in my mind and will continue to be a source of inspiration to me and others who have come to know him. I am proud to have lived along side a great individual and parent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A change called Lokpal]]></title>
    <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/2011/08/27/a-change-called-lokpal/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-27T21:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chocks.github.com/blog/2011/08/27/a-change-called-lokpal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few months, the Lokpal bill and the anti-corruption movement has gathered a lot of attention throughout India and some parts of the world. There have been many different views on the issue, many variations of thoughts from prominent people like civil society activist, spiritual leaders, industrialists, movie stars and the society as a whole.
<img class="right" src="http://im.in.com/connect/images/profile/promo_rhs_aug2010/Anna_Hazare_278x180_1.jpg" width="250" height="350" title="'Anna Hazare'" >
The underling message was clear - shout out to the government, the disgust and rage of the people about corruption. Sri Anna Hazare has become a national legend. It is indeed a very difficult battle especially in a democratic society and team Anna has played it neatly and nicely earning both respect and hearts of the masses. Like our PM expressed, I too respect and salute Sri Anna Hazare, team IAC and many others at the ramlila maidan who have lent their support for this cause.
 <!-- more -->
Watching the events unfold in the past few months, I am very pleased to see how India has responded and lent support to a universal cause. Above all what took me by surprise was finding how good orators we have in the house of the people. Impressive speeches and remarkable thoughts by many of our leaders like our PM, Sri Arun Jaitley, Shmt. Sushma Swaraj, Sri Pranab Mukerji and Sri. Rahul Gandhi is commendable. Critics apart, I felt really good seeing the nature of discussions happening in the house. The knowledge and oratory skills of some of our leaders are very impressive. I am also convinced that the most difficult job in the world is being the speaker of the Indian parliament, hats off to Meira Kumar.</p>

<p>Having followed the US debt-deficit debates for the last few months, I am quite convinced to see the debates and discussions happening in the Indian parliament are equally good. The only problem of our government has been their inability to decide. The PM (leader) is supposed to take an active role in engaging the people of the house, the protestors, the media and the people of India in every issue and dictate and direct the nature of happenings around. The role of any leader is the ability to take decisions and stand by them. If it turns to be a wise one, then he is indeed a capable leader. In this case the leader has not delivered.</p>

<p>This event showcases the power of democracy, a fight that brought down the government to its knees and reminded it of its functions. Governments that take office in the following years will be constantly reminded about this event and trigger a sense of fear in the minds of the office bearers.</p>

<p>On a personal note, I don’t entirely believe that just the Lokpal bill and Lokayutas will solve the problem of corruption, but it is definitely the right step forward. As Nandan Nilekani rightly pointed out and many others in the house reiterated that fact, it is a process; we will need layers of laws, reforms and charters to curb corruption, above all the right mindset. As Amir Khan said it all boils down to us, the people to decide if we will not take or give bribe throughout our lifetimes. On a lighter note, picture abhi baaki hai dhost! :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
