<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Eulogy | Play School]]></title>
  <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/categories/eulogy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chocks.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-01T18:21:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://chocks.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chockalingam Eswaramurthy (Chocks)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My grandfather – A grandson’s eulogy]]></title>
    <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/2012/01/11/my-grandfather-a-grandsons-eulogy/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-11T19:52:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://chocks.github.com/blog/2012/01/11/my-grandfather-a-grandsons-eulogy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Life can always be seen through a pair of “positive lens” or with a pair of “negative lens”, make sure you always pick the positive pair and see shortcomings as opportunities”. This is the mantra that forms the foundation of my value system. I have heard this quote in one form or other in many motivational speeches, but the person who instilled this mantra in me right from my very young age was my grandfather.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>
A self made, self-taught man with formal education of just 8th grade went on become a successful businessman and traveled across 60 countries in his career.
As my cousin once said, my grandfather’s life was a perfect story of rags-to-riches. Even after being immensely successful in life, he led a very simple life. His philosophy of success was a great family. His teachings in life were simple, just like Robin Sharma advises, my grandfather used to keep a routine of his mind and body. He was a going-to-bed-early-wake-up-early person. He was also a strict vegetarian; he once told me that he lived on raw spinach when he travelled abroad in 70’s.</p>

<p>My grandfather liked to challenge the obvious, because he believed and now I have to come to believe that great ideas are born by challenging the obvious and that will enable us to make an impact in the world.</p>

<p>I have probably learnt more from my grandfather than from my formal education.</p>

<p>Subroto Bagchi once wrote, “When great people move on, you don’t feel sad instead you feel a sense of vacuum”. This reflects my thoughts and loss accurately.</p>

<p>Though he’s not with us anymore, his teachings and values are etched in my mind and will continue to be a source of inspiration to me and others who have come to know him. I am proud to have lived along side a great individual and parent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
