<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Politics | Play School]]></title>
  <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://chocks.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-01T18:21:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://chocks.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chockalingam Eswaramurthy (Chocks)]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A change called Lokpal]]></title>
    <link href="http://chocks.github.com/blog/2011/08/27/a-change-called-lokpal/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-27T21:56:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://chocks.github.com/blog/2011/08/27/a-change-called-lokpal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few months, the Lokpal bill and the anti-corruption movement has gathered a lot of attention throughout India and some parts of the world. There have been many different views on the issue, many variations of thoughts from prominent people like civil society activist, spiritual leaders, industrialists, movie stars and the society as a whole.
<img class="right" src="http://im.in.com/connect/images/profile/promo_rhs_aug2010/Anna_Hazare_278x180_1.jpg" width="250" height="350" title="'Anna Hazare'" >
The underling message was clear - shout out to the government, the disgust and rage of the people about corruption. Sri Anna Hazare has become a national legend. It is indeed a very difficult battle especially in a democratic society and team Anna has played it neatly and nicely earning both respect and hearts of the masses. Like our PM expressed, I too respect and salute Sri Anna Hazare, team IAC and many others at the ramlila maidan who have lent their support for this cause.
 <!-- more -->
Watching the events unfold in the past few months, I am very pleased to see how India has responded and lent support to a universal cause. Above all what took me by surprise was finding how good orators we have in the house of the people. Impressive speeches and remarkable thoughts by many of our leaders like our PM, Sri Arun Jaitley, Shmt. Sushma Swaraj, Sri Pranab Mukerji and Sri. Rahul Gandhi is commendable. Critics apart, I felt really good seeing the nature of discussions happening in the house. The knowledge and oratory skills of some of our leaders are very impressive. I am also convinced that the most difficult job in the world is being the speaker of the Indian parliament, hats off to Meira Kumar.</p>

<p>Having followed the US debt-deficit debates for the last few months, I am quite convinced to see the debates and discussions happening in the Indian parliament are equally good. The only problem of our government has been their inability to decide. The PM (leader) is supposed to take an active role in engaging the people of the house, the protestors, the media and the people of India in every issue and dictate and direct the nature of happenings around. The role of any leader is the ability to take decisions and stand by them. If it turns to be a wise one, then he is indeed a capable leader. In this case the leader has not delivered.</p>

<p>This event showcases the power of democracy, a fight that brought down the government to its knees and reminded it of its functions. Governments that take office in the following years will be constantly reminded about this event and trigger a sense of fear in the minds of the office bearers.</p>

<p>On a personal note, I don’t entirely believe that just the Lokpal bill and Lokayutas will solve the problem of corruption, but it is definitely the right step forward. As Nandan Nilekani rightly pointed out and many others in the house reiterated that fact, it is a process; we will need layers of laws, reforms and charters to curb corruption, above all the right mindset. As Amir Khan said it all boils down to us, the people to decide if we will not take or give bribe throughout our lifetimes. On a lighter note, picture abhi baaki hai dhost! :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
